<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>random_jy</title>
    <link>http://randomjy.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on random_jy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Jon Young</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 21:39:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://randomjy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>name of the wind</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/name-of-the-wind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 21:39:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/name-of-the-wind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Name-Wind-Kingkiller-Chronicle/dp/0756404746&#34;&gt;The Name of the Wind&lt;/a&gt; by Patrick Rothfuss is the first of a 3 part fantasy series. The book is the &amp;ldquo;Day One&amp;rdquo; telling of a three day story by the books main character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book in the series is very much an &amp;ldquo;origin story&amp;rdquo; about how the main character, Kvothe, grew up and came to be famous. We get glimpses of the glory this young man is destined for, but we&amp;rsquo;re never introduced specifically to what makes him worth of a 3 day story telling binge. Kvothe evidently grows up to be one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most famous magicians, but we don&amp;rsquo;t get quite that far in the first book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story was slow going for me in the first few chapters, as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were building to. However, once the Kvothe starts telling his story in his words, the pace picks up quite a bit and things get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story reminds me a bit of another young lad with a predisposition to magic, Harry Potter. Both are orphans that suffer much through their childhoods, and both prove to be vary proficient with magic and a school that teaches just that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Kvothe is not just a magician, the school he attends actually teaches him how to survive in the real world, such as acting as a doctor, or a craftsman. Magic in this part of the story is relegated mostly to &lt;em&gt;Sympathy&lt;/em&gt;, willing the mind to control things. This of course if an over simplification of everything, and perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll get better after finishing the serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of the book refers to some &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; magic that Kvothe manifests out of anger. I think the next book might deal with how he comes to actually have control of that ability. The &amp;ldquo;Name of the Wind&amp;rdquo; is just one of many &amp;ldquo;Names&amp;rdquo; in the world - as all things have &amp;ldquo;Names&amp;rdquo; that can be called.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got going on this book, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put it down. It was well written, and the character development is phenomenal for the main character, but most other characters are given less time. I guess this makes sense - the main character is the one telling the story, and we all love to talk about ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enter the Matrix... err &#39;Neuromancer&#39;</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/neuromancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 21:10:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/neuromancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A co-worker recently turned me on to William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s 1986 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Neuromancer-William-Gibson/dp/0441569595&#34;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;, a Sci-Fi novel that ended up having quite the influence on the genre as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beginning of the book (and much of the middle) was a little confusing to me at times, as Gibson would drop technical expressions like we already knew what they were. Even if he quite clearly made them up. So I was left wondering just what the heck he was talking about. Somethings would get explained later, but most were not - even the important details. Perhaps if I had read his earlier works, things would have been much clearer. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big enough fan of his writing style to go investigate though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plot of the story centers around a junkie/hacker who is employed by a mysterious individual to bring about the destruction of a certain corporation&amp;rsquo;s servers. In the end we discover that it is all orchestrated by an Artificial Intelligence - living within those servers. The main character releases the AI into the world, and at various points in &lt;em&gt;the matrix&lt;/em&gt;, the AI even presents itself as a human. Still far fetched by today&amp;rsquo;s standards, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book does introduce some interesting concepts though. Things such as plugging directly into &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;cyberspace&lt;/em&gt;. And even the ability to be connected wireless-ly to the network. While we haven&amp;rsquo;t quite reached the same virtual world as described in the book, mobile devices certainly keep us attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help visualizing parts of the films &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Hackers&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/em&gt; while reading this book. Turns out, Gibson was the author of &lt;em&gt;Johnny Mnemonic&lt;/em&gt; as well! I&amp;rsquo;d recommend this book just to see the origin of some of the details that influenced Sci-Fi in the years after it was released.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XKCD&#39;s &#39;What If?&#39;</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/what-if/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 21:04:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/what-if/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine that the author of web comic &lt;a href=&#34;http://xkcd.com/&#34;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; wrote a book. Now stop imagining - it&amp;rsquo;s real. Randall Munroe wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/What-If-Scientific-Hypothetical-Questions/dp/0544272994&#34;&gt;What If?: Serious Scientific Answers to Absurd Hypothetical Questions&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;. interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book examines various scenarios that writers have submitted in various ways. Many questions are just too &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; to deal with, but others get a thorough examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learned from reading this book is: we&amp;rsquo;re all going to die. The earth is going to explode - there&amp;rsquo;s no way around it. Almost every question arrives at this conclusion. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that says more about the author, or the person asking these hypothetical questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; detailed explanations, and educated guesses, this book is for YOU!. I highly recommend the audio book version of this - read by everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite TNG hero, Wil Wheaton!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Report: &#39;Food: A Love Story&#39;</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/food-a-love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 20:54:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/food-a-love-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second book from Jim Gaffigan is called, &lt;a href=&#34;http://jimgaffigan.com/books/food-a-love-story/&#34;&gt;Food A Love Story&lt;/a&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s a great read if you want to be constantly hungry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is a tour of American cuisine through Gaffigan&amp;rsquo;s eyes. He breaks the country up into various regions based on the type of food it is known for. Other parts of the world are occasionally thrown in. This is of course all based on his comedy touring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned two things from this book: I should eat more hot dogs, and mustard is pretty great. The book inspired me to eat more hot dogs - with more mustard. I started with just the plain yellow mustard, but quickly progressed to Dijon, and then on to more exotic mustard types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also fun to hear a bit of back story / commentary on Gaffigan&amp;rsquo;s Hot Pocket bit. Kind of like a &amp;ldquo;Behind the Music&amp;rdquo; - but about food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the summer, the &amp;ldquo;Jim Gaffigan Show&amp;rdquo; started airing on TV Land / Comedy Central. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read his books, or heard his comedy, you&amp;rsquo;ll know most of the jokes in the show. Still, I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed watching it, and trying to get my wife to enjoy it as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on &#39;Delivering Happiness&#39;</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/delivering-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 20:49:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/delivering-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s summer time, and apparently that means I have less time for reading (the new kiddo may be affecting that as well). I am spending a lot of time outside doing yard work, so I’ve been making heavy use of audio books. In the past I’d listen to Pandora or NPR, but I think the audio book route is much more engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I listened to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Delivering-Happiness-Profits-Passion-Purpose/dp/0446576220/&#34;&gt;Delivering Happiness: A Path to Profits, Passion, and Purpose&lt;/a&gt; by Tony Hsieh. Hsieh is the CEO of &lt;a href=&#34;http://zappos.com/&#34;&gt;Zappos.com&lt;/a&gt;, an online retailer that started out with shoes, but has since expanded. I’ve bought several pairs of FiveTen’s from Zappos, so they must be doing something right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book details Hsieh’s journey to CEO of Zappos starting from when he was a kid. He got involved in some rather simple mail order businesses that did net him some spending money, which is pretty impressive. I relied on manual labor to make money as a kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I noticed is that all of the businesses Hsieh started or was involved with - he did it with his friends - and was met with great success. I think this plays into the culture focus later in the book - making work a place where you feel comfortable and &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999, Hsieh sold a company called LinkExchange to Microsoft for $265 million. He was soured after the sale to Microsoft because he now believes that the culture LinkExchange originally developed had disappeared. After that he bounced around a bit, but also started an start up incubator - which wasn’t as nearly ubiquitous as they are now. In this part of the book Tony seems to be “living the life” filled with parties and not a whole lot of responsibility. I think this is a pretty important time in the evolution of Hsieh and ultimately Zappos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zappos was just an investment until the incubator started to dry up, and then Hsieh went all in, eventually becoming CEO. The first few years for Tony at Zappos seemed kind of shaky, but the focus on the customer, and specifically their happiness, helped them grow to be a very profitable company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book details a lot of the troubles they had growing Zappos, which I appreciated. The book doesn’t try to paint a rosy picture all of the time – it acknowledges that growing a business is hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the later parts of the book, he discusses the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zappos.com/d/about-zappos-culture&#34;&gt;10 Core Zappos values&lt;/a&gt;. What’s important about these values is that they were derived from the entire employee base, over a year. It wasn’t the Leadership team at some retreat coming up with a “culture” and then presenting it to the company. The Zappos team set the values. That’s a pretty important distinction that I think lots of companies get wrong. If you’re going to focus on culture, get everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part of the book talks about the “Science of Happiness”. If you’re team isn’t happy, how can you hope to have positive interactions with your users? There are three components to building a happy team: &lt;em&gt;Autonomy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Mastery&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Purpose&lt;/em&gt;. Autonomy, responsibility, empowerment means giving employees real control over their destiny: what to work on and how to get it done. Purpose is the big one, a common motivating goal (or goals) for an organization. Does this all sound familiar, perhaps an Evolutionary Teal organization from &lt;a href=&#34;http://randomjy.com/posts/reinventing-organizations/&#34;&gt;Reinventing Organizations&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Zappos has recently made the move to Holacracy, which has been covered extensively in the media. The media has made a big deal about Zappos paying team members to leave if they aren’t excited about Holacrazy - only after they have read &lt;em&gt;Reinventing Organizations&lt;/em&gt;. As it turns out, Zappos has been doing this all along - they will pay you to leave the company if it’s not right for you. In this way, Zappos is &lt;em&gt;actually focusing&lt;/em&gt; on cultural fit. They don’t want the team to be soured by people that don’t want to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book. I appreciated learning the history and evolution of Tony Hsieh as a bussiness person. After reading &lt;em&gt;Reinventing Organizations&lt;/em&gt; some of the concepts in this book weren’t as mind blowing as they could have been, but it’s interesting to see that Zappos arrived at them independently (and later incorporated the same themes in the move to Holacracy). I learned a lot about Zappos, and I am certainly more inclined to think of them the next time I buy some shoes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on &#39;Reinventing Organizations&#39;</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/reinventing-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 20:36:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/reinventing-organizations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the privilege of reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Reinventing-Organizations-Frederic-Laloux/dp/2960133501&#34;&gt;Reinventing Organizations&lt;/a&gt; by Frederic Laloux - a book about the structure of organizations. This book looks at the various types of organizations in the work place, as well as a culture. I found it to be a fascinating read that really led me to reflect on how I bring my “self” to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is broken down into 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developmental Perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring Teal organizations (via Case Studies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next Steps: Evolving to “Teal”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In part 1, there is some background given on various levels of Human Consciousness and how they manifest within organizational structures. There are five developmental levels discussed - and each level is given a color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impulsive-Red&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conformist-Amber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achievement-Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pluralistic-Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolutionary-Teal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impulsive Red&lt;/em&gt; is the most basic state, and progress is made up to &lt;em&gt;Evolutionary-Teal&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Impulsive Red&lt;/em&gt; organizations are led by a single leader, and use Fear to exert control over the rest of the organization. Sadly I can say that I have worked in an organization like this. Lay offs were a common practice, happening every 6 months or so. People worked insane hours to get things done to stay on the “good list”. This type of behavior was a direct result from a lack of long term planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Conformist-Amber&lt;/em&gt;, an awareness of other people’s feelings was developed. These organizations still rely on a hierarchal command and control structure, but the roles are clear and well defined. &lt;em&gt;Amber&lt;/em&gt; organizations typically have a longer term focus. Examples of &lt;em&gt;Amber&lt;/em&gt; organizations include Military or School systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Achievement-Orange&lt;/em&gt; organization developed as part of the Industrial Revolution. In this state, a command and control mechanism exists for setting goals, but lower levels of the hierarchy are free to determine how to meet those goals. This organization has a focus on innovation and maximizing profits. Most of the companies I’ve worked for fall into the &lt;em&gt;Achievement-Orange&lt;/em&gt; paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pluralistic-Green&lt;/em&gt; starts to see the break down of command and control hierarchies. These organizations are values-driven and empower team members to do the right thing for the customer and the company. Ben &amp;amp; Jerry’s or Southwest Airlines are examples of &lt;em&gt;Green&lt;/em&gt; organizations. I’ve worked at a couple of organizations that have &lt;em&gt;Green&lt;/em&gt; tendencies, but often fall back to &lt;em&gt;Orange&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most recent development is &lt;strong&gt;Evolutionary-Teal&lt;/strong&gt;, with three significant breakthroughs, all discussed in Part 2 of the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Striving for Wholeness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolutionary Purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In talking about Teal, the author discusses the concept of Fear as a motivator. In Teal, fear is replaced with a sense of trust. This quote sums it up nicely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it comes down to this - fear is a great inhibitor. When organizations are built not on implicit mechanisms of fear but on structures and practices that breed trust and responsibility, extraordinary and unexpected things start to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;self-management:eb53e20e9a2b0969e5ecd2ae9a13400d&#34;&gt;Self-Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first marker of an Evolutionary Teal organization is Self-Management. Basically, letting an employee manage them selves, and yet we don’t:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know that a free-market system where a myriad of players pick up on signals, make decisions, and coordinate among themselves works much better. Yet for some strange reason, inside organizations, we still trust the equivalent of central planning committees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought this was a pretty strong metaphor. We have so much prosperity because we live in a free market - yet we remove that freedom as we drill down into the organizations that comprise the market. Why? This pretty much describes why we are seeing so many people start their own business - it’s the natural desire to self manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people ask me, “What do you do?” I always say “I’m a software engineer!”. I’m pretty proud of being an engineer, but what does that even mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking in terms of granular roles instead of pre-defined jobs creates great fluidity and adaptability. People can give up one role and take up another without needing to go through the cumbersome and often political process of appointment, promotion, and salary negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lead me to some introspection. I came up with this non-exhaustive list of the roles I currently have at work: Scrum Master, Automation Guy, Code Reviewer, Architect, Developer, QA, and Mentor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of those are my job title. But roles can extend beyond the workplace. What roles do I have in my personal life? Husband, Father, Son, Team mate. All of these roles make up the answer to “What do you do?” I’m going to try to give a more rounded answer of who I am the next time someone asks me that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-Management works as long as people follow an advice process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice process is a simple form of decision-making that transcends both consensus and unilateral action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advice process makes sure that an individual receives feedback before making a decision. It is important to note however, that an advice process does not have to be a “decision by committee”. Ultimately the individual asking for advice should be the one to make a decision. But seeking advice makes for a more inclusive environment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice process transcends this opposition beautifully: the agony of putting all decisions to consensus is avoided, and yet everybody with a stake has been given a voice; people have the freedom to seize opportunities and make decisions yet must take into account other people’s voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the advice process to work, everyone needs access to all the data. In a Teal organization, transparency is the default for all information. Laloux points out that secrecy within in an organization leads to a lack of trust:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any information that isn’t public will cause suspicion (why else would someone go through the trouble to keep it secret?), and suspicion is toxic for organizational trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once an organization is willing to trust it’s members, it becomes the member’s responsibility to produce results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom and responsibility are two sides of the same coin - you can’t have one without holding the other (at least not for long).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you impose self-management practices from above on distrustful workers, they are likely to take the freedom but refuse the responsibility, and you end up with a company headed for failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;striving-for-wholeness:eb53e20e9a2b0969e5ecd2ae9a13400d&#34;&gt;Striving for Wholeness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this section of the book, Laloux talks about bringing your full self to work. To do this, you bring everything from your home life to your work life (and back). This builds on the concept of multiple roles, but it’s more than that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you know about another person’s journey, the less possible it is to distrust or dislike that person. Want to know how to build relational trust? Learn more about each other. Learn it through simple questions that can be tucked into the doing of work, creating workplaces that not only employ people but honor the soul in the process. - Parker Palmer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team that knows each other can work together more efficiently. I learned this playing Ultimate Frisbee. A team made up of all stars that haven’t met before may take a while to start winning. However, a team that is attuned to each other can produce consistent “wins” more regularly. That’s why it was important to go out for dinner with your team! To get to know them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to change other people. We can only change ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to just one day say “ok I’m bringing my full self to work today.” It’s something you need to grow into, and will require work, it may even be scary. But the benefit will be huge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time our fears get triggered is an opportunity to learn and grow into more wholeness, reclaiming aspects of ourselves that we have neglected or pushed into the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing one’s whole self to work may or may not result in disagreements. Many of the Teal organizations profiled have an explicit conflict resolution process (sounds like the advice process):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Sounds True, all colleagues have the opportunity to learn a simple three-step process for difficult conversation: Step 1: Here is how I feel. Step 2: Here is what I need. Step 3: What do you need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that feedback becomes a very important part of bringing your whole self to every day. Receiving feedback can actually help one grow even more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we do, we can enter into beautiful moments of inquiry, where we have no easy answers but can help the colleague assess himself more truthfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side of the coin is that you must also be willing to provide feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been told that we should asses other people as objectively as possible. That’s a tragic mistake. Assessments are never objective (at best we can say the are culturally grounded, if many people share the same assessment), but nevertheless we often believe that they are. We turn our subjective impressions into “truths” about a person, no wonder they resist our feedback. Rather than cloaking ourselves in objective detachment, we must get involved. We must learn to speak in “I” language, to share how we have been inspired, touched, puzzled, hurt, frustrated, or angered as a result of what the other person has said or done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;evolutionary-purpose:eb53e20e9a2b0969e5ecd2ae9a13400d&#34;&gt;Evolutionary Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is my calling? What is truly worth achieving? Survival is no longer a fixation for Teal Organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section speaks to a higher calling - work is more than just a paycheck. How is your organization making you and the world better? Many of the companies profiled are focused on making the world better than they found it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paradox, of course, is that while they don’t have Orange’s obsession with growth, Buurtzorg, Patagonia, and the other organizations surveyed in this research have fantastic growth records. Teal practices unleash tremendous energies; when these energies meet a noble purpose and a deep hunger in the world, how could anything but growth ensue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding purpose of course can be difficult, but it’s not really something that you can lock yourself in a room and discover. It will most likely come organically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teal Organizations go about filling a need of the world not by tuning in to the noise of the world (the surveys, the focus groups, the customer segmentation), but by listening within. What product would we be really proud of? What product would fill a genuine need in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these next two quotes I found similarities to Agile or Lean Methodologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teal Organizations make peace with a complex world in which perfection eludes us. They shoot explicitly not for the best possible decision, but for a workable solution that can be implemented quickly. Based on new information, the decision can be revisited and improved at any point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas when we have invested much effort in defining the best solutions, we become attached to them and stick with them much longer than needed when things don’t turn out as planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first quote, it’s pretty much the definition of a Lean or Agile development process - iteration is key. The second quote defines a Waterfall approach to development. I’ve noticed however that it is possible to practice Agile, and still fall into the traps of Waterfall. The key is remembering that perfection is not attainable, and to push what you have!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid being full of ourselves (in service of our ego), we must strive to be self-less in service of a higher purpose. Teal paradoxical thinking invites us to transcend this either-or dichotomy: we can be both fully ourselves (rather than full of ourselves), and be working toward achieving an organization’s deeper purpose. We don’t need to reject parts of ourselves to be in service. It’s just the opposite: we are at our most productive and joyful when all of who we are is energized by a broader purpose that nourishes our calling and our soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results:eb53e20e9a2b0969e5ecd2ae9a13400d&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the book, Laloux gives a general overview of the companies he studied. No specific data is given, but instead summaries such as this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These companies are highly profitable, despite the fact that they seem to be, from an Orange perspective at least, quite careless about profits. Remember that they don’t make detailed budgets, they don’t compare budgets to actuals at the end of the month, they don’t set sales targets, and colleagues are free to spend any money they deem necessary without approval from above. They focus on what needs to be done, not on profitability, and yet this results in stellar profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the companies profiled, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.holacracy.org/&#34;&gt;HolacracyOne&lt;/a&gt; is a consulting company that helps organizations develop Self-Management styles. It lays out a organizational structure based on circles instead of a hierarchy. It also has guidelines for running meetings to ensure that the advice process is followed, and decisions are made efficiently. While not covered in this book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zappos.com/&#34;&gt;Zappos&lt;/a&gt; has recently made a switch to Holacracy for it’s organizational structure. The media has been following the Zappos transition closely, and I hope it’s successes are celebrated more than it’s failures. Instead, we should seek to learn from the failures and iterate to make Teal organizations more common place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wrap-up:eb53e20e9a2b0969e5ecd2ae9a13400d&#34;&gt;Wrap up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last parts of the book poses some interesting questions about where organizations could go as people elevate their Conciousness. We are of course at an exciting time in history where we have access to more and more. The only thing limiting us is - us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now ,the vast majority of human population has had to perform less-than-exciting work to make a living. For the first time in history, we can contemplate a future where all people, not just a happy few, are free to follow their calling, to live a life of creative self-expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book certainly challenged some of the way’s I think about work, and it’s purpose in my life. I’ve started wondering: “How can I live a fuller life? Is the path I’ve set forth on the one that will make me the happiest?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was just a fun quote - I’ve definitely noticed how growing a company too quickly can affect the &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; of a work place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right size of a workforce is equal to the number of people needed to make the workplace fun. Having too many employees demoralizes colleagues and causes turf battles. - Dennis Bakke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform - that was easy!</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/easy-tf-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 20:12:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/easy-tf-do/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Dyn gives engineers a couple of days every quarter to work on “off roadmap” projects. During the most recent one, I worked on various small projects, this is one of them! I wanted to experiment with &lt;a href=&#34;http://terraform.io/&#34;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt;, a tool for making your infrastructure declarable - treating it just like your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My example is simple, yet a great starting point; and I hope to expand on it soon. All I did was spin up a node and install NGINX. You can find the source for it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thejaywhy/easy_tf_do&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setup:e00c65342bed87d13765c0a31d6073e8&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need to set up a DigitalOcean account, if you don’t have one, you can use my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=38b47f5765f4&#34;&gt;Referral Link&lt;/a&gt; to get a free credit! (I get some too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a DO account, you’ll need to set up a “Personal Access Token” (PAT) for the API. and an SSH key setup as well. See these excellent DigitalOcean tutorials for how to do that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-the-digitalocean-api-v2#HowToGenerateaPersonalAccessToken&#34;&gt;How To Use the DigitalOcean API v2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-ssh-keys-with-digitalocean-droplets&#34;&gt;How To Use SSH Keys with DigitalOcean Droplets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, you’ll want to install Terraform. You can use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.terraform.io/downloads.html&#34;&gt;downloads page&lt;/a&gt; to get the appropriate package for your platform. I’m assuming you’re running from not Windows (sorry).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Terraform configuration assumes that the configuration variables are available via environment variables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ export TF_VAR_do_token={your_PAT}
$ export TF_VAR_ssh_fingerprint=$(ssh-keygen -lf ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | awk &#39;{print $2}&#39;)
$ export TF_VAR_pub_key=$HOME/.ssh/do_rsa.pub
$ export TF_VAR_pvt_key=$HOME/.ssh/do_rsa
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can pass in the variables to the Terraform command line interface:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ export DO_PAT={your_PAT}
$ export SSH_FINGERPRINT=$(ssh-keygen -lf ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | awk &#39;{print $2}&#39;)
$ terraform plan \
  -var &amp;quot;do_token=${DO_PAT}&amp;quot; \
  -var &amp;quot;pub_key=$HOME/.ssh/do_rsa.pub&amp;quot; \
  -var &amp;quot;pvt_key=$HOME/.ssh/do_rsa&amp;quot; \
  -var &amp;quot;ssh_fingerprint=$SSH_FINGERPRINT&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;usage:e00c65342bed87d13765c0a31d6073e8&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve’ got your DO access setup and your environment configured, you’re ready to go! Clone this repo if you haven’t done so already:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git clone https://github.com/thejaywhy/easy_tf_do.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to the fun part, planning out your deployment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terraform plan

+ digitalocean_droplet.web
    image:                &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;ubuntu-14-04-x64&amp;quot;
    ipv4_address:         &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    ipv4_address_private: &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    ipv6_address:         &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    ipv6_address_private: &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    locked:               &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
    name:                 &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;web-1&amp;quot;
    region:               &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;nyc3&amp;quot;
    size:                 &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;512mb&amp;quot;
    ssh_keys.#:           &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;1&amp;quot;
    ssh_keys.0:           &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;${ssh_fingerprint}&amp;quot;
    status:               &amp;quot;&amp;quot; =&amp;gt; &amp;quot;&amp;lt;computed&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which shows you exactly what this Terraform configuration is going to do. To apply it, all you have to do is run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terraform apply
# ...bunch of output....
Apply complete! Resources: 1 added, 0 changed, 0 destroyed.

The state of your infrastructure has been saved to the path
below. This state is required to modify and destroy your
infrastructure, so keep it safe. To inspect the complete state
use the `terraform show` command.

State path: terraform.tfstate

Outputs:

  ipv4 = &amp;lt;droplet public ip&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should now be able to visit the IP address and see the standard NGINX welcome screen. Hooooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://randomjy.com/img/nginx_hooray.png&#34; alt=&#34;NGINX - Hoooray!&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cleaning-up:e00c65342bed87d13765c0a31d6073e8&#34;&gt;Cleaning up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll assume you don’t want this super simple droplet to be eating into your wallet, you’ll probably want to shut it down! You could use the Web UI or another API wrapper, or use Terraform, it’ll be easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terraform plan -destroy
- digitalocean_droplet.web
$ terraform destroy
Do you really want to destroy?
  Terraform will delete all your managed infrastructure.
  There is no undo. Only &#39;yes&#39; will be accepted to confirm.

  Enter a value: yes

digitalocean_droplet.web: Refreshing state... (ID: 5364117)
digitalocean_droplet.web: Destroying...
digitalocean_droplet.web: Destruction complete

Apply complete! Resources: 0 added, 0 changed, 1 destroyed.
And that’s it! Super simple to make your infrastructure with code!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;infrastructure-as-code:e00c65342bed87d13765c0a31d6073e8&#34;&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was fun and all, but lets look at the actual code to see how we were able to spin up a DO droplet so easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the file &lt;code&gt;digitalocean.tf&lt;/code&gt; we specify the variables that we’ll use throughout our system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;variable &amp;quot;do_token&amp;quot; {}
variable &amp;quot;pub_key&amp;quot; {}
variable &amp;quot;pvt_key&amp;quot; {}
variable &amp;quot;ssh_fingerprint&amp;quot; {}

provider &amp;quot;digitalocean&amp;quot; {
  token = &amp;quot;${var.do_token}&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These variables, you may notice are the environment variables specified above in the Setup section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also specified a provider, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;digitalocean&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Terraform supports many of your favorite cloud services, such as AWS, Google Compute Engine, CloudFlare, Heroku, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One provider that is interesting is the Template provider. It lets you specify a template as part of your configuration, and pass variables to it. Terraform will render the file on another resource so that it can be consumed later. This is a step towards managing your configuration data with Terraform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other file we have, &lt;code&gt;www.tf&lt;/code&gt;, is a bit more complicated, and where the magic really happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Create a new Web droplet in the nyc2 region
resource &amp;quot;digitalocean_droplet&amp;quot; &amp;quot;web&amp;quot; {
    image = &amp;quot;ubuntu-14-04-x64&amp;quot;
    name = &amp;quot;web-1&amp;quot;
    region = &amp;quot;nyc3&amp;quot;
    size = &amp;quot;512mb&amp;quot;
    ssh_keys = [
      &amp;quot;${var.ssh_fingerprint}&amp;quot;
    ]

    connection {
      user = &amp;quot;root&amp;quot;
      type = &amp;quot;ssh&amp;quot;
      key_file = &amp;quot;${var.pvt_key}&amp;quot;
      timeout = &amp;quot;2m&amp;quot;
    }

    provisioner &amp;quot;remote-exec&amp;quot; {
      inline = [
        &amp;quot;export PATH=$PATH:/usr/bin&amp;quot;,
        # install nginx
        &amp;quot;sudo apt-get update&amp;quot;,
        &amp;quot;sudo apt-get -y install nginx&amp;quot;
      ]
    }
}

output &amp;quot;ipv4&amp;quot; {
    value = &amp;quot;${digitalocean_droplet.web.ipv4_address}&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this file we define a &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;digital_ocean&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;resource&lt;/code&gt; and name it &lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt;. Within the resource we specify what kind of droplet we want, and where it should go. There are two sub-blocks defined, &lt;code&gt;connection&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;provisioner&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;connection&lt;/code&gt; block tells Terraform how to connect to the resource, in this case via ssh. It also relies on the &lt;code&gt;ssh_keys&lt;/code&gt; field, which will place our public key on the node. We need the &lt;code&gt;connection&lt;/code&gt; specified before we can run our &lt;code&gt;provisioner&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;provisioner&lt;/code&gt; is a remote-exec type, but there are several others available, including a Chef implementation that will call out to your Chef server and converge against your run lists. The remote-exec resource is using a ssh connection to create a remote terminal, and then run commands to install NGINX - just like you would if you had SSH’d in to the remote node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another block included in the file, &lt;code&gt;output&lt;/code&gt;, that I used just to print out the IPv4 address of the droplet after a Terraform run. This just makes it easier to debug for the time being. We could however later add another resource to create a DNS A record that points at the IPv4 address. Maybe next time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:e00c65342bed87d13765c0a31d6073e8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terraform has made it &lt;em&gt;super simple&lt;/em&gt; to define your infrastructure as code, so why wouldn’t you? The Terraform CLI also provides a uniform way to manage your infrastructure across multiple cloud providers. No more worry about finding the right screen from a provider’s web UI, or writing your own API clients!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Report: Zero to One</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/zero-to-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 19:51:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/zero-to-one/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So, when you’ve got a newborn to take care off, reading is much harder. Luckily, there are audio books. I recently listened to Peter Theil &amp;amp; Blake Masters&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Zero-One-Notes-Startups-Future/dp/0804139296&#34;&gt;Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I obtained this audio book via my local library, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.overdrive.com/&#34;&gt;Overdrive&lt;/a&gt; app. This was my first experience with Overdrive, and it was OK. The app is a front to the overdrive website…and I have to keep signing in with my library card in addition to signing up for an Overdrive account. It’d be nice if the app remembered my library card info, ya know? The listening experience was excellent, and I appreciated the ability to speed up the reader. I listened at 1.5x, I tried listening at 2x but I wasn’t retaining much while doing other things. The speed up is pretty awesome, I didn’t have that the last time I listened to an audio book - The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy (on CD, again from my local library!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On to the book report! I found this book to be an interesting mash up of Theil’s own story with anecdotes about what has and has not worked. One of the themes that really struck me is that despite all the start up excitement and IPOs, we are actually making much technological advancement in a greater sense. There’s talk of how all the new start ups are looking to “disrupt”, but that’s not really creating something new, it is just incremental progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the sections that describe how “higher education” is failing America. People go to college and go through the motions of attending class, taking exams, and participating in extracurriculars for the sole purpose of landing a job post graduation. No one is learning how to think critically - how to solve problems. This is leading to stagnation in innovation not just in the “tech sector”, but other fields as well. I tend to agree with most of the statements in this book because I personally don’t feel as though I got much experience from my time at Clarkson. I believe I could have studied Electrical Engineering, and still followed the same career path. Indeed, that’s very true of many, many software developers - they don’t all study Computer Science or Software Engineering in school. In fact, I’m going to encourage my children not to attend a prestigious college - or any college at all. I think Higher Ed will drastically change in the next 15 years before they get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting section discussed the sheer number of failures in the Clean Tech Bubble. I have to admit I did not realize the bubble had occurred, but looking back I can see it. All of the failed solar companies that failed publicly as a result. In this section, Theil breaks down his “7 Questions for Product Innovation”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-engineering-questions-a-massive-technological-leap-not-incremental-improvement:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Engineering Questions - a massive technological leap, not incremental improvement&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-timing-question-when-are-you-entering-the-market-and-what-else-is-happening:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Timing Question - when are you entering the market, and what else is happening?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-monopoly-question-obtain-a-monopoly-by-being-truly-innovated:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Monopoly Question - Obtain a monopoly by being truly innovated&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-people-question-do-you-have-the-right-team-to-succeed:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The People Question - do you have the right team to succeed?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-distribution-question-how-will-sell:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Distribution Question - how will sell?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-durability-question-what-s-your-long-term-plan-how-will-you-continue-to-innovate:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Durability Question - what’s your long term plan? how will you continue to innovate?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-secret-question-secrets-are-problems-that-haven-t-been-solved-yet:a6e4896c68ee2eedf26f48b3afc61dbf&#34;&gt;The Secret Question - Secrets are problems that haven’t been solved yet.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theil says if you don’t have an answer to all 7 questions, then you aren’t innovating. He cites Tesla as an example of a clean tech company that meets the 7 question criteria - and look at them, they keep killing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The questions made a lot of sense to me, especially the People Question. You can’t hire a bunch of “rock stars” and expect magic. You need to create a team that’s united, not just in product vision, but outside of work too. I learned this playing Ultimate Frisbee. If you want your team to gel on the field, it takes more than practices and drills. You need to actually know your teammates if you want to reach greatness on the field… or in business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other interesting points in the book, but the Education system deficiencies and the 7 Questions are really what stuck with me. The other major theme in the book is that monopolies are good - it allows companies to invest in innovation outside of their core compentencies. See: Google and all of the other stuff they build besides Search and Online Advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed the book, although at times I thought it was rambling or repeating itself. I guess this comes from the fact that the book is based off a collection of essays given during a course at Standard (were Theil studied - that point you will not miss). And it was a good re-introduction to audio books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad is Fat - Review</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/dad-is-fat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 13:31:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/dad-is-fat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently finished reading Jim Gaffigan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Dad-Fat-Jim-Gaffigan/dp/0385349076/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1425148385&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=dad+is+fat&#34;&gt;Dad is Fat&lt;/a&gt;. It was a great read, I definitely laughed out loud every chapter. My wife was not amused. Reading this book put me back on track for my 2015 goal of 2 books a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is basically a collection of essays about how Gaffigan came to have a family with 5 children, living in a 2 bedroom apartment in NYC. That&amp;rsquo;s crazy, I only have 1 kid (so far) and that&amp;rsquo;s more than enough work. 5 kids? Working nights doing stand up? When does he sleep? He admits to not really ever sleeping. Still impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A general theme throughout the book is Gaffigan&amp;rsquo;s wife, Jeannie, and how she makes everything work (even his stand up). He even correctly refers to himself as just another one of the kids. I know my wife often thinks &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have two children, but at least I only have to change diapers for the&lt;/em&gt; actual &lt;em&gt;kid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m in no hurry to grow up, especially when I&amp;rsquo;m spending time with kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite chapter of the book is where Gaffigan compares the role of the Dad to that of Vice President. A figurehead, with no real power. I often feel this way, my kid will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; go for Mom. I really am just someone to play with. But I wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s because I spend so much time at work, instead of in the house? Gaffigan seems to spend a lot of time with his kids, but he&amp;rsquo;s still just VP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve got kids, and free time, you should definitely checkout &lt;em&gt;Dad is Fat&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll find a lot of stuff to relate to in there. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have kids, you&amp;rsquo;ll still find laughs, but you may be scared away from having kids for ever. Maybe even skip the whole marriage thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to reading Jim Gaffigan&amp;rsquo;s next book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Food-Love-Story-Jim-Gaffigan/dp/0804140413/ref=pd_sim_b_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;refRID=1SGD8NJM1565YNSBCG4R&#34;&gt;Food: A Love Story&lt;/a&gt;. I will no doubt get a few dirty looks from my wife while I laugh my way through that book too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January/February 2015 Reading List</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/remote-rework-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 20:02:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/remote-rework-win/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for 2015 is to read 2 books a month.  I made this goal towards the end of the January, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pleased to say I got one book done in January, and &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; in the first seven days of February. Now I just need to finish another one to get my average back on track. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting copies of these books from my local library. The great thing about my library is that it is a part of a system of libraries that make it easy to borrow books from any library in the area. It really expands the number of books I have at my disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rework-remote:d60164a73e516b5e526672678dfb4449&#34;&gt;Rework &amp;amp; Remote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://37signals.com/rework&#34;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, and followed it up with &lt;a href=&#34;https://37signals.com/remote&#34;&gt;Remote&lt;/a&gt;, both by the founders of &lt;a href=&#34;https://37signals.com&#34;&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt; Both of these books are a pretty easy read, a collection of short essays more than anything. Also each essay comes with a nifty illustration. My favorite line from either book is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A stuffed backlog is a stale backlog&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really hit home for me as a Scrum Master. Our backlog is packed with stuff that we&amp;rsquo;ll get to &amp;ldquo;some day&amp;rdquo;. Using your backlog for a place to capture ideas is doing it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say there&amp;rsquo;s anything revolutionary about either of these books, but they are a both a solid, quick read, worth your time if you work in the Tech Industry. It looks like they have a third book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Real-Smarter-Successful-Application/dp/0578012812/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1423358012&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=getting+real+37+signals&#34;&gt;Getting Real&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ll probably check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-win-friends-influence-people:d60164a73e516b5e526672678dfb4449&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other book I finished in February was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/How-Friends-Influence-People-Revised/dp/067142517X/ref=sr_1_5?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1423357609&amp;amp;sr=1-5&amp;amp;keywords=how+to+win+friends+and+influence+people&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People&lt;/a&gt;. I find this book on lots of people&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;must read&amp;rdquo; lists. And I can understand why: the book is good at teaching you things you should just know. The book teaches through many, many anecdotes that lead to a single principle for each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this book helpful in changing how I communicate with others. I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought of myself as someone who lives by the Golden Rule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do unto others as you would have done unto yourself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the problem is, how I like to be treated is irrelevant when talking with other people. I like my conversations to be short and to the point, and let logic prevail. That&amp;rsquo;s not really what communication is all about for most people. This book has helped me really understand that. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably need to re-read this one every few months to keep myself from sliding back to my very direct conversational style.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolutions for 2015</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/posts/resolutions-for-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 19:57:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/posts/resolutions-for-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Now that it is February, time to make some goals for myself in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-an-even-awesomer-husband-father:87223ae63adbc1cf20a73dc9414eb665&#34;&gt;Be an even awesomer Husband &amp;amp; Father&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think I&amp;rsquo;m doing a pretty decent job at this already, but there&amp;rsquo;s always room for improvement. And our family will be expanding from 3 to 4 in 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-a-blog-and-keep-writing-for-it:87223ae63adbc1cf20a73dc9414eb665&#34;&gt;Make a blog&amp;hellip; and keep writing for it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you&amp;rsquo;re here, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing pretty well so far. Of course, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can keep going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written what I&amp;rsquo;ve got so far using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty sweet static site generator written in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. I like that I can write everything in markdown. After using github for a couple of years, I have problems writing in anything other than Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-2-books-a-month:87223ae63adbc1cf20a73dc9414eb665&#34;&gt;Read 2 Books a Month&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I averaged maybe 1 book a month. I read mostly fiction in 2014. In 2015 I&amp;rsquo;m looking to read both fiction and non-fiction. Ideally one of each type every month. Not sure how the other goals will affect this one. I plan to make time to read in the mornings, after I wake up. Hopefully the house will still be quiet at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;re-implement-this-blog:87223ae63adbc1cf20a73dc9414eb665&#34;&gt;Re-Implement this blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is definitely a stretch goal, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to try re-implementing this blog using various frameworks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rails (no experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;django (some experience from work stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elixir (no experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go &amp;amp; its magnificent stdlib (some experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I&amp;rsquo;ll write the blog apps to intake the same markdown used by Hugo. And then take advantage of various CI/CD pipelines to deploy new posts too all the apps at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the log term plan becomes use DNS tricks to randomly send users to a different destination. They&amp;rsquo;ll only know what type of framework they are seeing by a &amp;ldquo;bug&amp;rdquo; in the footer. Sounds neat, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://randomjy.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 19:54:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://randomjy.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;person:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Person&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s up! Who am I? Why am I subjecting you to my random thoughts? Because we&amp;rsquo;re on the Internet, and I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off I&amp;rsquo;m married with 1 kid already and another on the way. My family is pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe in doing as much as I can myself, so I like to build or improve things around our house. Plus, nothing will make you appreciate just how lucky you are more than doing manual labor. I dug dirt in the summers before college, it definitely motivated me to become an Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college I studied Computer Engineering &amp;amp; Software Engineering. After I worked in Embedded Systems, mostly coding up DSP type stuff in C. Although there were some deviations, including Java and Ada. Yes, Ada, and I liked it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a days I work at &lt;a href=&#34;https//dyn.com&#34;&gt;Dyn&lt;/a&gt; working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://chef.io&#34;&gt;Chef&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.varnish-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Varnish&lt;/a&gt;. I serve as the Technical Owner &amp;amp; Scrum Master in our Agile/Scrum process. I am thoroughly enjoy working with my Squad as we build out a new SOA based web portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to learn new things and improve on what I already know. This blog will hopefully capture that never ending journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to contact me, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/random_jyoung&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkedin.com/in/jonryoung/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; would be best, Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tech:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Tech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org&#34;&gt;vim&lt;/a&gt; for everything. I have trouble using other editors that don&amp;rsquo;t natively support &lt;code&gt;h/j/k/l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; (and isn&amp;rsquo;t it awesome?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base theme is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x&#34;&gt;Hyde-X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further theme inspriation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://npf.io/&#34;&gt;npf.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>